<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>J S G  on Jean-Sébastien Gonsette</title>
    <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in J S G  on Jean-Sébastien Gonsette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Almost Ultimate Passwords Management Guide for a Safe Digital Life </title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/ultimatepasswordguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/ultimatepasswordguide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The difficult question of our digital life security has only become more complex over the years, due to our increasingly massive use of all kinds of digital content. As the financial stakes behind our data can sometimes be colossal, it is normal that from the beginning they have aroused the greed of all kinds of unscrupulous people. And it goes without saying that, even if all kinds of mechanisms have been put in place to better protect our data, the techniques to steal it have never stopped growing in ingenuity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Artificialis Intelligentia et Circenses</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/buddy/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/buddy/part1/</guid>
      <description>The notion of artificial intelligence is a concept whose traces can be found up to more than 1000 years before our era, but which experienced an especially lightning rise from the 19th century with the work of many mathematicians and engineers who began to formalize its principles. Then, a convergence of innovative ideas at the dawn of the 20th century established a close connection with this field as soon as it appeared that the brain was made up of neurons processing electrical impulses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Comment or Not to Comment ?</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/codecomments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/codecomments/</guid>
      <description>No, you should not stop writing code comments. The Internet is undeniably a tremendous technology that has literally propelled information sharing and exchange of ideas to a level never achieved before. Nevertheless, this sometimes provokes some frustrations, as when we read the words of a person whose thinking and conclusion are fundamentally at the opposite of ours. It may generate a serious sense of urgency that causes you to react in one way or another, because you are aware of a crime of lese-majesty; someone, somewhere on the Internet is wrong!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Long Way of Backtracking</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/part1/</guid>
      <description>Although the origin of Sudoku goes back as far as the last century, a surge of popularity can be noted during the year 2005. I remember it particularly well, because it was at that time that I discovered them while I was going to winter sports. I guess I had to come across a collection of grids at a gas station, during one of our stops to our destination. This totally new concept for me occupied me some time, the time to solve some grids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Ambition, Architecture and Design</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/buddy/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/buddy/part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is more in the realization of a generic platform for board games than in the implementation or the study of the best algorithm existing in this field. It is therefore important to clearly define the constraints that we want to fulfil in order to sketch the solution accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why consciousness and quantum physics are inextricably linked</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/quantum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/quantum/</guid>
      <description>The mystery of the origin of the Universe is certainly one of the most profound and mysterious that humanity can face. Because even if physics become complete and get a model and equations to understand the smallest excitement of the quantum world that composes it, the reason for the existence of such a Universe would remain unfathomable. And it is important to specify that the word &amp;ldquo;unfathomable&amp;rdquo; must be understood here in the original sense of the term: nothing nor anybody can ever provide the slightest sketch of an explanation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right Way to Pave the Grid</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The method used previously to fill the grid was excessively naive, because it is quite catastrophic to wait the grid is full before to test the validity of the solution. The problem being combinatorial, the exponential nature of the combinations of words appears as so many branches and twigs subdividing frightfully quickly. So it is better to realize as soon as possible that the chosen path is rather a dead end, so as to cut off the dead branch as soon as possible and avoiding to lose valuable computing time in the depths of its tree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/contact/</guid>
      <description>About Me I hold a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Civil Electrical Engineering from the Polytechnic Faculty of Mons in 2003, as well as a specialized Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Control and Embedded Systems from ISAE-SUPAERO in 2004. I then worked for 6 years at Thales on the development of satellite control benches, including Galileo. In 2010, I left the aerospace field to enter the automotive world, at AW. This was also an opportunity for me to reconnect with my first loves by working, among other things, on artificial intelligence topics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>