<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jean-Sébastien Gonsette</title>
    <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jean-Sébastien Gonsette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Almost Ultimate Passwords Management Guide for a Safe Digital Life </title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/ultimatepasswordguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/ultimatepasswordguide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The difficult question of our digital life security has only become more complex over the years, due to our increasingly massive use of all kinds of digital content. As the financial stakes behind our data can sometimes be colossal, it is normal that from the beginning they have aroused the greed of all kinds of unscrupulous people. And it goes without saying that, even if all kinds of mechanisms have been put in place to better protect our data, the techniques to steal it have never stopped growing in ingenuity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Comment or Not to Comment ?</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/codecomments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/codecomments/</guid>
      <description>No, you should not stop writing code comments. The Internet is undeniably a tremendous technology that has literally propelled information sharing and exchange of ideas to a level never achieved before. Nevertheless, this sometimes provokes some frustrations, as when we read the words of a person whose thinking and conclusion are fundamentally at the opposite of ours. It may generate a serious sense of urgency that causes you to react in one way or another, because you are aware of a crime of lese-majesty; someone, somewhere on the Internet is wrong!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why consciousness and quantum physics are inextricably linked</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/quantum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/posts/quantum/</guid>
      <description>The mystery of the origin of the Universe is certainly one of the most profound and mysterious that humanity can face. Because even if physics become complete and get a model and equations to understand the smallest excitement of the quantum world that composes it, the reason for the existence of such a Universe would remain unfathomable. And it is important to specify that the word &amp;ldquo;unfathomable&amp;rdquo; must be understood here in the original sense of the term: nothing nor anybody can ever provide the slightest sketch of an explanation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>