<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wizium on Jean-Sébastien Gonsette</title>
    <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wizium on Jean-Sébastien Gonsette</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Long Way of Backtracking</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/part1/</guid>
      <description>Although the origin of Sudoku goes back as far as the last century, a surge of popularity can be noted during the year 2005. I remember it particularly well, because it was at that time that I discovered them while I was going to winter sports. I guess I had to come across a collection of grids at a gas station, during one of our stops to our destination. This totally new concept for me occupied me some time, the time to solve some grids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right Way to Pave the Grid</title>
      <link>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsgonsette.github.io/en/projects/wizium/part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The method used previously to fill the grid was excessively naive, because it is quite catastrophic to wait the grid is full before to test the validity of the solution. The problem being combinatorial, the exponential nature of the combinations of words appears as so many branches and twigs subdividing frightfully quickly. So it is better to realize as soon as possible that the chosen path is rather a dead end, so as to cut off the dead branch as soon as possible and avoiding to lose valuable computing time in the depths of its tree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>